<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on hannah here</title><link>https://blog.hannahlin.me/en/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on hannah here</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>潮潮</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 10:33:32 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.hannahlin.me/en/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Random Summary 01</title><link>https://blog.hannahlin.me/en/p/2024-01/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 22:11:29 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hannahlin.me/en/p/2024-01/</guid><description>&lt;img src="https://blog.hannahlin.me/zh-cn/p/2024-01/cover.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Random Summary 01" />&lt;p>Generally speaking, the beginning of 2024 has been very busy and fulfilling. Apart from not exercising at all and not reading a word book, it is all as expected. I thought that I would be able to get active in the New Year and start reading, but I found an excuse to postpone it until after the exam. &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-happened">What happened&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Go to work&lt;/strong>: Got my first job to work in a nice office with nice colleagues and really enjoying what I&amp;rsquo;m working on. Once proved with experience that the industry is a better place for me than the academic. As I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m actually contributing to something tangible and the time is totally worth it with the feedback and fulfillment (and of course the money)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://blog.hannahlin.me/zh-cn/p/2024-01/office.jpeg"
width="2243"
height="2117"
srcset="https://blog.hannahlin.me/zh-cn/p/2024-01/office_hu16082729476735806584.jpeg 480w, https://blog.hannahlin.me/zh-cn/p/2024-01/office_hu1610196744907607325.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Image"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="105"
data-flex-basis="254px"
>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Got a 4.0&lt;/strong>：Just after sighing that the study environment in Germany gives people a sense of comfort when they can fail and start over again, I received the first hang-up in my life. Because I failed to meet the word count requirement for a peer review assignment in one seminar, the doctoral student who taught this course stammered and told me, &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m sorry, we can&amp;rsquo;t let you pass, it&amp;rsquo;s not fair to the others&amp;rdquo;. The theory of hindsight did reveal that they had an annotated minimum word count, which I should have glanced at when I was writing the assignment, but my brain didn&amp;rsquo;t process the word &lt;em>minimal&lt;/em> at all&amp;hellip; Sort of a not-so-serious lesson. However, I have also reflected on my attitude towards seminar, because there is only a distinction between passing and failing, so it&amp;rsquo;s all about eating the old money and not being very committed to doing it, and now a lot of the opportunities are from previous undergraduates doing the coursework based on their interest and enthusiasm to help me fight for it, so I&amp;rsquo;d better be serious about doing seminar next semester.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>A lot of presentations&lt;/strong>：At the end of January, I intensively conducted three seminar presentations, and made almost 50 pages of PowerPoint. although I still need notes to help me, but it&amp;rsquo;s not like the first presentation in December when I just read from the notes, I&amp;rsquo;m getting more and more comfortable of using English. It&amp;rsquo;s true that the more I put my heart into the project, the more I&amp;rsquo;m able to report it, for example, the best one is the one that I did all by myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Got two 1.0&lt;/strong>：I got perfect scores on the first two ORAL exams and was very happy. However, at first I felt that it was a bit unreal, and I even thought that I would be told later that I was wrongly evaluated and that I would have to take back my grades. After all, the teacher of one of the courses said just before the exam that it was almost impossible to get a 1.0, but he was very happy to congratulate me on getting a perfect score that day. For a moment, I wondered if he had lowered his standards because I was an Asian woman. But that&amp;rsquo;s just a bad habit of doubting yourself before something good happens, and in the end, of course, I accepted the result with confidence.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&amp;ldquo;Confidence is the realization of one&amp;rsquo;s own promises to oneself,&amp;rdquo; and after looking back at my schedule, I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good thing that I was able to prepare for all three exams at the same time and get at least seven and a half hours of sleep every day, even though I had about 20 hours a week to devote to my job. Quite proud of myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>Cooking&lt;/strong>：I tried to make fried chicken, thanks to the cheap and large amount of solid oil in the supermarket, I unlocked fried food. I also unlocked sandwich making, which is better and cheaper than Mensa food. I don&amp;rsquo;t have to have awkward small talk with my classmates in the cafeteria. before, I would alternate one day of pasta and one day of rice, but the frequency of pasta has increased significantly in the past few weeks, because of its convenience and hassle-free nature. I don&amp;rsquo;t cook a lot of stir-fry dishes, but I mainly make a stew with roasted vegetables, and udon noodles go with everything. On New Year&amp;rsquo;s Eve, I used the gyoza skins I bought to make gyoza that I could eat for two weeks, and the best place for chives is in the gyoza.
&lt;img src="https://blog.hannahlin.me/zh-cn/p/2024-01/food.jpeg"
width="977"
height="745"
srcset="https://blog.hannahlin.me/zh-cn/p/2024-01/food_hu10541461475005056062.jpeg 480w, https://blog.hannahlin.me/zh-cn/p/2024-01/food_hu16023774956647886602.jpeg 1024w"
loading="lazy"
alt="Image"
class="gallery-image"
data-flex-grow="131"
data-flex-basis="314px"
>&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="plan-ahead">Plan Ahead&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>There are still a few exams to go, but there will still be plenty of free time. The more vague plan is to continue sketching, as well as going to the gym twice a week, being able to read immersively, and swiping through fewer running videos. German will still have to be learned, even though the A1.1 exams are sparse.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>